Finding aid to Ginling College (Nanjing, Jiangsu Sheng, China) records CA.MS.00016
Smith College Archives
Ginling College records
1915-1993
Smith College Archives
Ginling College (Nanjing, Jiangsu Sheng, China).
CA.MS.00016
3.333 linear feet (9 containers)
Foreign Sister College to Smith College. Contains notes, letters, reports, photographs, articles, and bulletins from Alumnae Committee members, Ginling College students and faculty, and others involved with Ginling.
Biographical / Historical
Ginling College opened in 1915 with six faculty and eleven students, the product of the imagination of a group of American women educators stranded in Shanghai in 1911, all refugees from the revolutionary turmoil in central China. One was Matilda Thurston, who became the first president of the College. She graduated from Mount Holyoke in 1896, and went to China in 1913 to find a location for Ginling, hire faculty, and recruit students. It was only in 1907 that the Chinese emperor issued an edict favoring education for women in China. The Revolution of 1911 marked a new beginning, and Ginling College was ultimately founded by five mission boards -- Northern Baptists, Disciples of Christ, Northern and Southern Methodists, and Northern Presbyterians. Each board pledged US$10,000 for buildings and equipment, the support of a representative on the teaching staff, and a contribution of US$600 toward current expenses.
Ginling graduated its first class in 1919; thus Wu Yi-fang, who would later become president of the College in 1928, and four other women became the first women in China to receive fully accredited Bachelor of Arts degrees. All subjects were taught in English except for the Chinese classics.
Smith's relationship with Ginling began in 1916. Through the enthusiasm of Delia Leavens '01 and Frederica Mead '11, both of whom had spent considerable time in China, the Smith College Association for Christian Work adopted Ginling as its foreign project. Their first campus contribution in 1916 amounted to $1,000 and was made annually until 1921, when it was raised to $2,500, due to increasing interest in Ginling. It was also in 1921 that Smith officially recognized Ginling as its "Little Sister in the Orient." During the difficult period of war, the contribution reached $4,000 a year. The Smith Alumnae Committee for Ginling was started in 1923, and Smith alumnae donated $50,000 for the construction of a recreation building in Ginling. Also, annual contributions to the current expenses of the College gradually increased until it reached a maximum of $5,500 a year.
Throughout the increasing turmoil in China, the relationship between Smith and Ginling flourished. The Sino-Japanese War began in 1937, and in 1938 Ginling College decided to go into exile in West China Union University in Chengtu. Smith raised almost $2,500 as a gift to Ginling to celebrate its twenty-fifth birthday in 1940, and this money was used for repairs after the war. The Smith College Alumnae Committee for Ginling was expanded in 1941 to include students and faculty. By 1942, fifteen Smith alumnae had taught at Ginling.
In 1943, Dr. Wu Yi-fang visited Smith to receive an honorary LLD. She brought the gift of a satin scarf bearing the signatures of all the Ginling seniors and an accompanying letter from them to Smith's 1943 graduating class, expressing their gratitude for their concern and help. After the new People's government was established on October 1, 1949, Dr. Wu was recognized as a leader in China and was asked to serve on various committees for education, women's rights, and community service. She began working to change the curriculum and the administration of Ginling so it would be acceptable to the new government.
The new government pushed for self-support and Chinese leadership in all its institutions, especially those connected with overseas schools and religious groups. In 1950, the U.S. and China cut off all financial transactions with each other. In 1951, Ginling was combined with the University of Nanking to become National Ginling University under government control. Smith was greatly troubled by these changes, and many Smith students and faculty wanted to transfer the Ginling support to Tunghai University in Taiwan, to which a number of Ginling College supporters had gone. Smith was frustrated by the confusion of the situation, so alumnae groups were notified not to collect funds for Ginling and by March 1954 most local Ginling committees had disbanded.
Ginling College re-opened in 1987 with sixteen students in a two-year course in Applied English in Nanking Normal University. In order for the government to permit it to re-open, Ginling had to provide courses that were unique, different from the others offered in Nanjing Normal University. In 1995, Ginling had 300 students in three programs -- Applied English, Nutrition and Food Sciences, and International Accounting. Ginling is also developing a year-long training program for around 100 women teaching in rural middle schools. The College is funded mainly by the government, although it does receive some private donations from Ginling alumnae and the Wu Yi-fang Memorial Foundation.
Scope and Contents
The Ginling College Records cover a period from 1915 to 1993. However, the majority of the materials span the time when interaction between Smith and Ginling was at its peak, from 1920 to 1950. A large quantity of the material is composed of letters, reports, photographs, and publications. Other types of material represented in the collection include articles, published works, and other memorabilia.
The collection includes many letters from alumnae committees regarding the development of Ginling College, as well as minutes from meetings. Insight into the political turmoil rampant in China during the period can be gained from the reports of Ginling administrators and faculty. The Ginling College budgets are also included, with the breakdown of spending on various areas.
There are also a few papers on the history of Ginling College, most notably a book by Mrs. Lawrence Thurston, the first president of the College. Faculty files, such as that of Dr. Wu Yi-fang, detail what it was like to live and teach at Ginling at that particular period. Letters, notes, and bulletins of various organizations associated with Ginling also give one a sense of the early history of the college. There are records from the Association of Christian Colleges in China, the Board of Directors, the Board of Founders, and the United Board of Christian Colleges in China.
Photographs of buildings, students, and faculty in various time periods, accompanied by descriptions, also give one a feel for campus life. There are many newsletters on events and developments at Ginling, as well as brochures and course bulletins. Publications of student organizations and the President's reports also prove a good source of information on life at Ginling.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into five series:
I. Alumnae Committee for Ginling College
II. Ginling College: General
III. Organizations
IV. Photographs
V. Publications
Conditions Governing Access
Materials in the Smith College Archives are open for use, with the following exceptions: "Office Files," files of records created for the use of the administrative unit that created them, are closed to research for a period of 10 years following their creation.
Faculty tenure and promotion files, as well as inactive faculty files are closed permanently. Board of Trustees' records are closed permanently. Minutes of the Faculty Council are closed to all except current Smith College Faculty for a period of 75 years following their creation. Student academic records, student disciplinary records, and all records containing FERPA-covered student information are closed during the lifetime of the student. Student records created 100 years or more ago are assumed to be about deceased students. In all cases, the College Archives will continue to provide public access to materials that were intended to be public at the time of their creation (press releases, publications, etc.)
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Source unknown
Women's colleges--China.; Universities and colleges--China.; Ginling College (Nanjing, Jiangsu Sheng, China).
- SERIES I. ALUMNAE COMMITTEE FOR GINLING COLLEGE, 0.98 linear feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series includes letters from various members of the Alumnae Committees, reports from Ginling College faculty and administrators, minutes from meetings of committees, and lists of Ginling alumnae and supporters. The letters, spanning a period from 1920 to the 1950's, give great insight into the progress of Ginling, from its tentative early stages to the eventual parting of Smith and Ginling due to China's tense political situation. The folders are arranged chronologically, and contain a mixed of typed and handwritten letters, notes, and reports.
  - Alumnae Committee for Ginling College, 1920-1950 (Box 1331, Folder 1)
  - Alumnae Committee for Ginling College, 1936-1937 (Box 1331, Folder 2)
  - Alumnae Committee for Ginling College, 1938-1940 (Box 1331, Folder 3)
  - Alumnae Committee for Ginling College, 1941-1943 (Box 1331, Folder 4)
  - Alumnae Committee for Ginling College, 1944-1945 (Box 1331, Folder 5)
  - Alumnae Committee for Ginling College, 1946-1947 (Box 1331, Folder 6)
  - Alumnae Committee for Ginling College, 1948 (Box 1331, Folder 7)
  - Alumnae Committee for Ginling College, 1949 (Box 1331, Folder 8)
  - Alumnae Committee for Ginling College, 1950 (Box 1331, Folder 9)
  - Alumnae Committee for Ginling College Smith reports, 1951-75 (Box 1332, Folder 1)
  - Alumnae Committee for Ginling College, 1952-1953 (Box 1332, Folder 2)
  - Alumnae Committee for Ginling College, 1954 (Box 1332, Folder 3)
  - Alumnae Committee for Ginling College, 1955 (Box 1332, Folder 4)
  - Alumnae Committee for Ginling College, 1956-1957 (Box 1332, Folder 5)
  - Alumnae Committee for Ginling College, 1958-present (Box 1332, Folder 6)
  - Alumnae Association Ginling College Record Book, June 1975 (Box 1332, Folder 7)
  - Alumnae Association, undated (Box 1332, Folder 8)
- SERIES II. GINLING COLLEGE: GENERAL, 0.49 linear feet
  This series contains not only a comprehensive history of Ginling College, but also articles from Smith Alumnae Quarterly, records and letters from Ginling alumnae, and files of faculty members Wu Yi-fang and Frederica Mead Hiltner. Letters, articles, pamphlets, reports, and booklets comprise the history of Ginling. In particular, there is a report entitled "Remembering Our Sisters in China" by Patricia N. Page (1945) and a book "Ginling College" by Mrs. Lawrence Thurston and Ruth M. Chester. Page's report looks back on Ginling's early history, focusing particularly on President Wu Yi-fang and Smith's relationship with the college. Thurston and Chester's book is a broader look at Ginling, from its inception as a pioneer women's college to its alliance with the University of Nanking in the 1950's.
  - Alumnae Quarterly Articles, Feb. 1950 - May 1951 (Box 1333, Folder 1)
  - Alumnae Reunion, 1983 (Box 1333, Folder 2)
  - Anniversary - "Smith Around the World", 1925 (Box 1333, Folder 3)
  - Anniversary - 1940 (Box 1333, Folder 4)
  - Alumnae in U.S.- Ginling Association in America, 1939-1966 (Box 1333, Folder 5)
  - Faculty - Hiltner, Frederica Mead, 1967-1977 (Box 1333, Folder 6)
  - Faculty - Wu, Yi-Fang (Box 1333, Folder 7)
  - Gifts from Ginling, 1925-1950 (Box 1333, Folder 8)
  - History of Ginling, 1921-1940 (Box 1333, Folder 9)
  - History, 1941-1981; undated (Box 1333, Folder 10)
  - History: Ginling College, 1945-1955 (Box 1333, Folder 11)
  - History: Far East Conference Minutes, 1950 (Box 1333, Folder 12)
- SERIES III. ORGANIZATIONS, 0.49 linear feet
  This series is composed mostly of letters and bulletins from the Associated Board of Christian Colleges in China, whose name was later changed to the United Board of Christian Colleges in China in 1948. Meetings address what actions to take with Ginling, what policies to implement, and how to go about doing this. The notes, letters, and minutes span a period from 1931 to the 1950's, and are arranged chronologically.
  - Associated Boards of Christian Colleges in China, 1931-1941 (Box 1334, Folder 1)
  - Associated Boards of Christian Colleges in China (Box 1334, Folder 2)
  - Associated Boards of Christian Colleges in China, 1946-1947 (Box 1334, Folder 3)
  - Board of Directors: Minutes, 1932 (Box 1334, Folder 4)
  - Board of Founders, 1937-1945 (Box 1334, Folder 5)
  - United Board of Christian Colleges in China, 1948-1949 (Box 1334, Folder 6)
  - United Board of Christian Colleges in China, 1950 (Box 1334, Folder 7)
  - United Board of Christian Colleges in China, 1951 (Box 1334, Folder 8)
  - United Board of Christian Colleges in China, 1952-1954 (Box 1334, Folder 9)
  - United Board of Christian Colleges in China, 1956-1993 (Box 1334, Folder 10)
  - United Board of Christian Colleges in China: Publications, 1934-1954 (Box 1334, Folder 11)
  - Photograph album (Box 1335)
- SERIES IV. PHOTOGRAPHS, 0.735 linear feet
  This series contains photographs of Ginling. The folders are divided chronologically. There is an album that contains pictures of the campus, faculty, and students. Most of the photographs, both candid and posed, are accompanied by descriptions. There are photos of Ginling's original campus as well as Ginling in Chengtu. In addition, there are little scrapbooks made by various Ginling students.
  - Photographs, pre 1920 (Box 1336, Folder 1)
  - Buildings, 1920 (Box 1336, Folder 2)
  - Photographs, 1920-1925 (Box 1336, Folder 3)
  - Photographs, 1939-1938 (Box 1336, Folder 4)
  - Photographs, 1939-1940 (Box 1336, Folder 5)
  - Photographs, 1940-1941 (Box 1336, Folder 6)
  - Photographs, 1942-1990 (Box 1336, Folder 7)
  - Alumnae Association 25th Anniversary, 1940 (Box 1336, Folder 8)
  - Alumnae Association 40th Anniversary, 1955 (Box 1336, Folder 9)
  - Alumnae Association Exhibit, 1949 (Box 1336, Folder 10)
  - Faculty, undated (Box 1336, Folder 11)
  - Jenshow - Ginling's Rural Project, undated (Box 1336, Folder 12)
  - Ginling in Chengtu, Szechuan, 1939 (Box 1336, Folder 13)
  - General photographs, undated (Box 1336, Folder 14)
- SERIES V. PUBLICATIONS, 1.225 linear feet
  This series is divided up into brochures, bulletins, newsletters, magazines, and student activities. The newsletters make up a large part of the series, and are arranged chronologically. These document the events at Ginling, as well as developments in its history. The course bulletins allow one to see the direction Ginling has taken academically. There are also copies of the Ginling College Magazine, and the news articles and editorials they contain reflect student opinion. The President's reports and publications of student organizations are also included in this series.
  - Brochures, 1915-1934 (Box 1337, Folder 1)
  - Brochures, 1935-1950 (Box 1337, Folder 2)
  - Bulletins, 1915-1931 (Box 1337, Folder 3)
  - Bullentins, 1961 (Box 1337, Folder 4)
  - Calendars, 1924-1952 (Box 1337, Folder 5)
  - Newsletters
    - Newsletters, 1922-June 1937 (Box 1338, Folder 1)
    - Newsletters, Sept. 1937-Mar. 1938 (Box 1338, Folder 2)
    - Newsletters, Apr. 1938 -1939 (Box 1338, Folder 3)
    - Newsletters, 1940-1944 (Box 1338, Folder 4)
    - Newsletters, 1945-1946 (Box 1338, Folder 5)
    - Newsletters, 1947-1948 (Box 1338, Folder 6)
    - Newsletters, 1949-1950 (Box 1338, Folder 7)
    - Newsletters, 1951-1957 (Box 1338, Folder 8)
    - Newsletters, 1940-1950 (Box 1338, Folder 9)
  - News from Schwen Hwa Cheng, undated (Box 1338, Folder 10)
  - President's Reports, 1915-1920 (Box 1338, Folder 11)
  - Recipe Book, 1940 (Box 1338, Folder 12)
  - Student Activities
    - Ginling College Magazine, 1924-1928 (Box 1339, Folder 1)
    - General, 1943 (Box 1339, Folder 2)
    - General (Box 1339, Folder 3)